Max Patton

linkedin.com/maxrp factormrp.github.io (949) 374-6884 riverapatton.max@gmail.com

DATA ENGINEER / ANALYST / BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE DEVELOPER

Experienced professional with extensive training in data modeling, cleaning to power visualizations used in operational decision making. Possess strong technical skills, with the ability to translate important data into cohesive and actionable stories for non-technical audiences. Additional academic training in machine learning, software construction, C, Python, and site-reliability engineering.

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Data Visualizations / Storytelling / PowerBI / Tableau / SAS
- AWS EC2 / Azure Cloud / Salesforce / Datadog / RDBMS / DAX
- Version Control / Git / Scripting / Make / Bash / Linux / Docker
- Software Engineering / Machine Learning / Predictive Analytics
- Hypothesis Testing / Insight Generation / Root-cause Analysis
- Technical Translation / Communication / Creativity
- Python / Airflow / Pandas / NumPy / Pytorch
- Data Modeling / Dimensional Design / R / M
- Query Optimization / Snowflake / Databricks / SQL
- ETL Implementation / Data Management / dbt
- Data Science / Fast Prototyping / Excel / VBA
- Process Innovation / Automation / RPA

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

09/2022 - 05/2024

Datavant is the largest healthcare data connectivity provider in the United States driven by the mission to improve patient outcomes.

- Implemented a monthly KPI report, garnering the attention of 25+ senior operational leads and upper management executives.
- Ensured seamless workflows and met stringent SLAs invariant to complexity, achieving a 98% on-time deliverable rate.
- Instrumental in a \$4.3M renewal, showcasing adeptness in strategic decision-making and enabling the revitalization of lucrative business channels.

Business Intelligence Developer

10/2021 - 08/2022

Pulmuone Foods USA is a lifestyle of health and sustainability corporation (LOHAS) dedicated to the mission of providing plant-based alternatives to the American food market.

- Created interactive dashboards to serve a stakeholder base of over 30 sales reps and 10 upper management executives. Improved operational reactivity by 10%.
- Optimized complex SQL queries on large datasets in Microsoft SQL Server by leveraging dimensional design and indexing to achieve speedups from 2x up to 163x.
- Implemented best practices into codebase by applying Twelve-Factor-App methodology, adding version control, and writing well-defined documentation for future maintainers.

Supply Chain Management Analyst

06/2021 - 10/2021

Pulmuone Foods USA

- Created innovative scripts for identifying demand trends and recommending inventory management optimizations, turning a multi-hour process into a 5 minute run-and-review.
- Tasked with the important responsibility of directing inventory management decisions for a key customer account, decreasing the product shortages during the period of management by 50%.
- Interfaced cross-functionally with Sales, Operations, & Management to promote proactive status updating and align on shortage minimization, resulting in 4% more on-time, in-full (OTIF) deliveries.

EDUCATION

B.S. Math of Computation w/ Entrepreneurship Minor - University of California Los Angeles (2021, 3.4 GPA)

Relevant Coursework (Math): Machine Learning, Data Science, Software Construction, Probability, Algorithms, Discrete Structures, Linear Algebra, Game Theory, Applied Numerical Methods, Mathematical Imaging, Operating Systems

Relevant Coursework (Entrepreneurship): Social Networking, Product Design, Principles of Economics, Entrepreneurship and Venture Initiations, Business Plan Development, Finance and Accounting

A.A. Physics - Saddleback College (2019, 3.8 GPA) & A.A. Math - Saddleback College (2019, 3.8 GPA)

REFERENCES

Christine Horne (Datavant) christine@datavant.com

Adam Estrada (Pulmuone) 310-595-8832